#### **RESEARCH STATEMENT**

As a prospective Ph.D. student, my research interests lie at the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), participatory design, and mental health. Using qualitative methods, I aim to investigate and design technology which supports the management of mental health conditions. I am especially interested in how technology can critically engage with the public- and self-stigmas associated with mental health conditions, as well as vulnerable populations which lack access to mental health resources.

#### **EDUCATION**

2020 - Dec 2023 (Expected) B.S., Informatics, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Thesis: Examining the Role of Reflective Technology Within Bereavement and

Meaning-Making

Advisor: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung

Minors: Human-Centered Computing, English

GPA: 4.0

#### **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

**Undergraduate Researcher**, Proactive Health Informatics, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Sep 2022 -

Probing the Role of Technology in Pro-Choice Abortion Activism

Present Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Dr. Elizabeth Kaziunas, Dr. Katie Siek

Co-led a study investigating technological needs of pro-choice Indiana abortion activists. Designed cultural probe with participatory methods, and currently planning second study mapping the sociotechnical space of Indiana abortion activism via probe.

May 2022 -Present Examining the Role of Reflective Technology Within Bereavement and Meaning-Making

Advisor: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung

Co-led a study investigating design opportunities for reflective systems to support bereaved individuals. Designed and conducted qualitative diary and interview study, and analyzed findings through the lens of constructivist grief therapies.

Sep 2021 -Present Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences

Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Aswati Panicker

Continued previous REU project; assisted with finalizing probe design and provided design input during probe development. Currently planning field deployment.

May - July 2021

**REU Research Intern**, Proactive Health Informatics REU Site, Indiana University Bloomington, USA

Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences Advisors: Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung, Aswati Panicker

Collaboratively designed a cultural probe investigating the digital sharing of cooking experiences between distanced family members. Conducted user research, iteratively designed probe, and conducted usability testing.

Jan – May 2021 **Undergraduate Research Assistant**, Undergraduate Research Opportunities in Computing (UROC), Indiana University Bloomington, USA

*Influence of Conspiracy Theories on Human Information Interactions* 

Advisor: Dr. Devan Donaldson

Assisted with paper revisions and journal re-submission. Conducted literature review, wrote paper sections, and conducted data re-analysis.

## **PUBLICATIONS** -

### **Refereed Conference Posters**

2023 "I Don't Need a Megaphone to Be Helpful": Probing the Role of Technology in Pro-Choice Abortion Activism

Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW) DOI: 10.1145/3584931.3606980

<u>Colin LeFevre</u>, Aswati Panicker, Sitha Vallabhaneni, Nikhil Dinesh, Forum Modi, Katie Siek, and Chia-Fang Chung

2022 Cooking Stories: Connecting Remote Families Through the Sharing of Cooking Experiences

European Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (ECSCW) DOI: 10.48340/ECSCW2022 P11

Forum Modi, Colin LeFevre, Nikhil Dinesh, Aswati Panicker, and Chia-Fang Chung

#### **Refereed Journal Articles**

2022 Records, trust, and misinformation: Using birtherism to understand the influence of conspiracy theories on human information interactions

Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology

DOI: 10.1002/asi.24697

Devan Donaldson and Colin LeFevre

### **Lightly Reviewed Workshop Papers**

2023 "A Safe Space to Think About Grief": Reflecting on Bereavement Through Video Games and Experiential Metaphor

Workgroup on Interactive Systems in Healthcare (WISH) Symposium, Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)

Colin LeFevre and Chia-Fang Chung

#### **Articles Under Review**

N/A New Understandings of Loss: Examining the Role of Reflective Technology Within Bereavement and Meaning-Making

Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2024 Papers

Colin LeFevre and Chia-Fang Chung

	TEACHING EXPERIENCE
Spring 2022, Fall 2022, Spring 2023	<b>Undergraduate Instructor</b> , Department of Informatics, Indiana University Bloomington, USA INFO-I 300 Introduction to Human Computer Interaction
	Instructors of Record: Dr. Phil Jordan, Dr. Chia-Fang (Christina) Chung
	Closely mentored groups of 10-15 students on user research, ideation, and prototyping. Created comprehensive set of tutorials on UX / UI prototyping software (Figma). Coordinated weekly instructional team meetings and led grader training.
	- HONORS & AWARDS
	Indiana University Bloomington
2020 – Present	Luddy Scholar, Provost Scholar, & Luddy SICE Direct Admit
2020 – Present	Luddy School Dean's List
2022, 2023	Luddy Undergraduate Instructor Teaching Excellence Award
	- SERVICE
	Indiana University Bloomington
2022 - Present	Student Representative, Informatics Undergraduate Curriculum Committee
	ACM Conferences
2023	Student Volunteer (In-Person), Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW)
2023	External Reviewer, Posters (x1), Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW)
2023	Student Volunteer (In-Person), Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)

# SKILLS -

## **HCI Research**

Interviews, Cultural Probes, Diary Studies, Ethnography, Participatory Design, Qualitative Coding, Thematic Analysis

## **UX Design**

User Research, User Personas, Protoyping, Usability Testing, Affinity Mapping

# **Technical / Programming**

Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Native, Arduino Prototyping

## Tools

Google Workspace, Figma, Miro, Overleaf, Saturate, Taguette